(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T09:11:03.808817",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ギラギラな beach way 夏の flow again
The dazzling beach way, summer flow again
願っては身勝手な 一夜の game
Hoping for a selfish, one-night game
ロックオン 君を待ってたんだ but don't know you
Rock on, I've been waiting for you, but I don't know you
ギラギラな瞳で 口説く play 途中も
Seducing with glittering eyes along the way
横切った ビキニ ガン見の scope
A bikini crosses my line of sight in scope
ロックオン 一人だけ
Rock on, all alone
ロックオン 苦渋の選択
Rock on, a tough choice
ああ 神に逆らってでも この刺激に満ちた季節を終わらせない
Ah, even if it means going against God, I won't let this stimulating season end
夏が今 僕の心 広げてく
Now summer is opening up my heart
波風 笑い声が
The waves, the wind, and the laughter
laka laka love laka laka love
この空 雲 虹に乗っかって
Riding on this sky, clouds, and rainbow
砂浜の 君の足跡 見つけ出すから
I'll find your footprints in the sand
laka laka love laka laka love
夜は群がって ビーチ向かいの bar
At night, gathering at the bar across the beach
今宵も探す 恋愛のゲーム
Tonight too, searching for a love game
俺が司令塔 そして特攻きる
I'm the playmaker and I'll make the charge
お前はアシスト パスを出す ok?
You give the assist pass, ok?
行こうか
Shall we go?
夜の同士達よ 企みだらけのただれた関係
Comrades of the night, a festering relationship full of plots
ロックオン 当たっても砕けるな
Rock on, don't break even if you hit
ロックオン かりそめの月に惑わされて
Rock on, bewitched by the temporary moon
事情なんかより先に行動
Acting before any circumstances
近づく唇がドギツイハバネロ言語 それも悪くない
Approaching lips, harsh habanero language, that's not bad either
夏が今 僕の心 広げてく
Now summer is opening up my heart
波風 笑い声が
The waves, the wind, and the laughter
laka laka love laka laka love
この空 雲 虹に乗っかって
Riding on this sky, clouds, and rainbow
高い山 見下ろして 耳澄ましたら
Looking down from the high mountain and listening closely
laka laka love laka laka love
no lonely no lonely 愛に裏切られてきたけど
no lonely no lonely, though I've been betrayed by love
lonely lonely 心の中は
lonely lonely, inside my heart
nobody knows 答えは波のしらべ
nobody knows, the answer is in the melody of the waves
探す 足跡 消えてゆく前に
before the footprints I'm searching for disappear
君の光の色が 広がっていく
the color of your light is spreading out
波風 笑い声が
The waves, the wind, and the laughter
laka laka love laka laka love
この空 雲 虹に乗っかって
Riding on this sky, clouds, and rainbow
砂浜の 君の足跡 見つけ出すから
I'll find your footprints in the sand
夏が今 君と僕を引き寄せる
Now summer draws you and me together
沈まない 太陽が
The sun that never sets
laka laka love laka laka love
海よ 春も 秋も 冬も 飲み干してゆけ
O sea, drink up spring, autumn, and winter
まだまだ 終わらせない この夏は
I won't let this summer end yet
laka laka love laka laka love
ギラギラの beach way 夏の flow Again
The dazzling beach way, the summer flow again
願っては身勝手な 一晩の game
What I'm wishing for is a selfish one-night game
ロックオン 君を待ってたんだ
Rock on, I've been waiting for you
ラカラカララブ ラカラカラ海よ！
Laka laka laka love, laka laka laka sea!
春も 秋も 冬も 飲み干してゆけ
Drink up spring, autumn, and winter!
まだまだ 終わらせない
We're still not done yet!
この夏は…… ああ、ラカラカララブ ラカラカララブ
This summer is... Ah, laka laka laka love, laka laka laka love!
イェーイ！
Yay!
Lonely, lonely 目には見えない その愛は
Lonely, lonely, that invisible love...
Lonely 今のままじゃ 見つけられないんだよ
Lonely, as it is now, we can't find it.
Lonely, lonely 心に嘘をついても
Lonely, lonely, even if you lie to your heart...
あーー！
Aaaah!
あれ？あれみんな聞いてたの？
Huh? Wait, were you all listening?
ああ、こんばんすーーる！ 白金ノエルの
Ah, good evening-ru! It's Shirogane Noel's...
100万人記念3Dライブです！ イェーイ！見てるー！
1 million subscriber celebration 3D live! Yay! Are you watching?!
今日は、団長の100万人記念の3Dライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Danchou's 1 million subscriber 3D live today!
やっぱね、1曲目と言ったらこの曲っしょ！
As you know, for the first song, it's gotta be this one!
ちょっとまだ夏は来てないけど、シャカビーチを歌わさせていただきました！イェーイ！
Summer isn't here quite yet, but I sang "Shaka Beach"! Yay!
はあ〜、ねえ、しかもね、あのハッシュタグも
Haah~, hey, and besides, there's also a hashtag,
あるのでね、えーと、あ、こっちだこっち。あの、白金ノエル100万人記念3Dライブで
so... um, ah, over here, over here. Um, with "#ShiroganeNoel1M3DLive",
いっぱい写真を撮ったり、あの、感想をつぶやいたりして、目指せ！
please take lots of photos, tweet your impressions, and let's aim for...
トレンド…うーん、3ぐらいに入れたらいいなということで、よろしくお願いします！イェーイ！
Trend... um, hopefully top 3 or so, so please support us! Yay!
はあ、っち、あっち。なんかもうね、夏だね！なんか全然さ、なんか6月って感じしなく、
Haah, it's hot, it's hot. It really feels like summer! It doesn't feel like June at all,
あ、めちゃ暑いんですけど、まあ、この暑さに負けないシャカビーチだったんじゃないかなと思います。
ah, it's super hot though, but I think this was a Shaka Beach that won't lose to the heat.
ちょっと団長のこのサングラス姿もいっぱい撮ってください、ピチッ！
Please take lots of pictures of Danchou in these sunglasses too, *pich!*
はあ〜、ね、普段、ま、歌枠とかで歌ってるんだけど、やっぱ3Dってなると、こう動きがつくから、
Haah~, you know, normally I sing in singing streams and stuff, but when it's 3D, it comes with movement,
あの、団長いつもね、こう、ジズマンの、いい太陽を！エー、ラカラカララブ、ラカラカララブ、
so Danchou is always like, "Jizman's good sun! Eh, laka laka love, laka laka love",
って手はね動いてるんだけど、実態はさ、でもやっぱこうやって全身で歌うのは、
her hands are moving, but actually, singing with my whole body like this,
やっぱちょっと大変だなと思いました。
is actually pretty tough, I felt.
いや本当に、みんなも、まだまだね、これからもライブ続きますんで、ちょっと、
Yeah really, everyone, since the live will continue for a while longer, um,
団長の勇姿をね、見ててください。もしもしたら、この、この、ま、いつもの衣装じゃなく、
please keep watching Danchou's brave figure. Who knows, maybe this... this... not our usual outfit,
ま、お馴染みのね、あの衣装にも着替えるかもしれないんで、今のうちにこの写真撮っといてください、ピュッ！
but maybe changing into that familiar outfit, so please take a photo of this right now, *pew!*
あ、最近ね、牛さんになったから、もうもう…って、猫か、なんか分かんないな、牛さんのポーズって分かんないや、もう、
Ah, recently I became a cow, so moo moo... wait, a cat? I don't really know, I don't know cow poses, moo...
もうもう、というわけでよろしくお願いします！あれ、あ、てかここ、もしかして、やっぱ牛さんだと、あ、待って、見てみんな！ほら！
Moo moo, with that said, thank you! Huh, ah, wait, here, maybe, if it's a cow, ah, wait, look everyone! Look!
やっぱビーチだからさ、沈む、しず…沈まない太陽！見て、ほら！団長と、いや本当はね、これ水着だったらよかったんだけど、
Because it's a beach, you know, sinking, sink... a sun that doesn't sink! Look, see! Danchou and, well honestly, it would have been nice if this was a swimsuit,
ちょっとねYouTube君が興奮しちゃうから、ちょっと誰の水着もないんだよ、でもみんなの心の中でね、団長を水着にしてしてください。見てるー？
but YouTube-kun gets excited, so we don't have any swimsuits, but in everyone's hearts, please imagine Danchou in a swimsuit. Are you watching?
いや、いいねこれ。あ、あー、びしゃびしゃ！あ、びしゃびしゃ、びしゃびしゃ！見てこの、
Man, this is nice. Ah, ahh, soaking wet! Ah, soaking wet, soaking wet! Look at this,
水の感じが、や、冷たいな水！ちょうどいいわ。
the water feeling, man, the water is cold! It's just right.
いやなんかさ、このね、ビーチ、この、団長ね、選んだ理由があるんだけど、
Man, you know, there's a reason why Danchou chose this beach,
あの、ここ、SSSでね、あの、先輩方がその水着でわあって歌ってて、ちょうど団長、3期生がデビューする前だったから、
um, here, in SSS, you know, our seniors were singing in swimsuits, and just before Danchou and Gen 3 made their debut,
あの、ま、なんかい、そん時には3Dもなく、ま、水着もなくって感じで、憧れてたんだけど、
um, well, back then there was no 3D, and no swimsuits, and I admired it, but
いやでも団長もこうやってね、SSSじゃないが、こう先輩たちのビーチで歌えて、ハッピーハッピーです！キチキチキチチ！
yeah, but Danchou too, being able to sing like this on our seniors' beach (even if not in SSS), I'm happy happy! *kichikichichichi!*
すごいね、こんな感じ水が、はーい！第3キャ、は、キャハハって感じで、ちょっと1人だと寂しいな。
Amazing, water like this, haai! Third ca-, ha, kahaha, it feels kind of lonely being by myself.
なんか、寂しい団長、ちょっと1人でね、前から言ってるけど、1人でソロライブってなんかちょっと辛い。ライブするの辛いから、
Somehow, lonely Danchou, I've been saying from before, doing a solo live by myself is kind of tough. Doing a live is tough, so
なんと、これから先、ちょっと素敵なゲストをお呼びしているので、そちらに、そちらもよろしくお願いします！
miraculously, from here on, we're inviting some wonderful guests, so please look forward to that as well!
#白銀ノエル100万人記念3Dライブ
[Shirogane Noel 1M Subscribers 3D Live]
皆様、本日はお忙しい中、多数ご参加くださいまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Everyone, thank you so much for attending today despite your busy schedules.
まずは、皆様方の御健康を祝して、
First, to toast to everyone's good health...
乾杯！
Cheers!
日本全国酒飲み音頭
[Song: Nippon Zenkoku Sakenomi Ondo]
1月は正月で酒が飲めるぞ
In January we can drink sake for New Year's,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
2月は豆まきで酒が飲めるぞ
In February we can drink sake for bean-throwing,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
3月はひな祭りで酒が飲めるぞ
In March we can drink sake for Doll's Day,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
4月は花見で酒が飲めるぞ
In April we can drink sake for cherry blossom viewing,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
5月は子供の欲で酒が飲めるぞ
In May we can drink sake for Children's Day,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
6月は田植えで酒が飲めるぞ
In June we can drink sake for rice planting,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
7月は七夕で酒が飲めるぞ
In July we can drink sake for Tanabata,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
8月は暑いから酒が飲めるぞ
In August we can drink sake because it's hot,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
9月は台風で酒が飲めるぞ
In September we can drink sake for typhoons,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
10月は運動会で酒が飲めるぞ
In October we can drink sake for Sports Day,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
11月は何でもないけど酒が飲めるぞ
In November we can drink sake for no particular reason,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
12月はどさくさで酒が飲めるぞ
In December we can drink sake in the hustle and bustle,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
よしっ！それでは続いて日本全国飲み歩いていこう！まずは北海道から！
Alright! Then let's continue walking around drinking across all of Japan! First, from Hokkaido!
秋田はきりたんぽで酒が飲めるぞ
In Akita we can drink sake for kiritanpo,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ　酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
山形はさくらんぼで酒が飲めんだの
In Yamagata we can drink sake for cherries,
酒が飲めんだの　酒が飲めんだの
We can drink sake, we can drink sake!
茨城は納豆で酒が飲めっぺよ
In Ibaraki we can drink sake for natto,
酒が飲めっぺよ　酒が飲めっぺよ
We can drink sake! We can drink sake!
静岡はお茶と一緒に酒が飲めるずら
In Shizuoka we can drink sake along with green tea,
酒が飲める飲めるずら　酒が飲めるずら
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
京都は舞妓はんと酒が飲めるだす
In Kyoto we can drink sake with maiko,
酒が飲める飲めるだす　酒が飲めるだす
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
富山は越中ふんどしで酒が飲めるぞ
In Toyama we can drink sake in Etchu loincloths,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ　酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
岡山はきびだんごで酒が飲めるぞな
In Okayama we can drink sake for kibidango,
酒が飲める飲めるぞな　酒が飲めるぞな
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
愛媛は伊予柑で酒が飲めるでのお
In Ehime we can drink sake for iyokan citrus,
酒が飲める飲めるでのお　酒が飲めるでのお
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
長崎はカステラで酒が飲めんばってん
In Nagasaki we can drink sake for castella, but...
酒が飲める飲めるばってん　酒が飲めるばってん
We can drink, drink sake, but we can drink!
鹿児島は西郷高盛と酒が飲めるちよ
In Kagoshima we can drink sake with Saigo Takamori,
酒が飲める飲めるちよ　酒が飲めるちね
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
沖縄は行ったことないけど酒が飲めるぞ
In Okinawa we've never been, but we can drink sake,
酒が飲める飲めるぞ　酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
日本全国どこへ行っても酒が飲めるぞ
Across all of Japan wherever we go, we can drink sake!
酒が飲める飲めるぞ　酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
酒が飲める酒が飲める酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink sake, we can drink sake, we can drink sake!
酒が飲める飲めるぞ　酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, drink sake, we can drink sake!
あー…　起きるとするか。
Ah... Time to get up.
起きっか。
Let's get up.
飲んだ！お早うございます！
I drank! Good morning!
どうしよう。なんだ…
What should I do? My head...
頭が…
My head hurts...
頭痛いな。なんだ…
My head hurts. What is this...
はーい！本当に、お二人さん、来て下さり、ありがとうございます！
Yay! Seriously, thank you both so much for coming!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あけましておめでとう おめでとうございます
Happy New Year, congratulations!
とりあえずね、いっぱい乾杯してね、お酒飲んだからさ
First of all, we've had plenty of toasts and drinks,
乾杯、乾杯、乾杯！
cheers, cheers, cheers!
飲んでるけどね
Though we're already drinking.
いやね、もうリスナーさんはねみんな知っとると思うんですけど、この3人
Now, I think the listeners all know this, but these three—
知ってますか？このなんでこの3人なのか？
do you know why it's these three?
なんと我ら、ほろ、酒飲み組、組！
Believe it or not, we are the Holo sake-drinking group!
いえーい！
Yay!
いや今初めてやった。
That was our first time doing that.
はじめてちょっとね、いきなりね、食い込んじまった。
We just jumped right into it suddenly.
なのでちょっと団長ね、このホロ酒飲み組で、やっぱやりたいことって言ったら、やっぱこのね、有名なこのお酒の歌をね、歌って、そのなんか親睦をさらに深めたいなと思って
So as the leader, for what I want to do with this group, I wanted us to sing this famous drinking song to deepen our bond even further.
いやほんとに来てくれ、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
いや、よかったよかった、ほろライブくしのね酒好きさん達だからね。
I'm so glad, since we're the biggest drinkers in Hololive.
そうです！やりたかったのよ、こういうの！
Exactly! We've always wanted to do this!
温泉よ！
Hot springs!
ね、アキロゼ先輩でおちょこあるのにもう忙しいからここやってさおちょことかでもないスタイル
Akirose-senpai has a sake cup, but she's so busy she's not even using a cup style.
途中からこっちになっちゃうね、どうしてもね。もっとちっちゃいもんね。これ入れてらんないみたいな
It inevitably ends up like this halfway through. It's too small, like you can't pour enough in.
いやでもこうやってね、やっぱ酒瓶を持ってる姿ってなかなか
Still, seeing us holding sake bottles like this isn't something you see very often.
うんうん。せっかくね、お写真とかね、やっぱ撮っちゃおうか記念撮影。いいね、いいね。
Yeah. So let's take a commemorative photo! Sounds good, sounds good.
じゃあ、何に撮ろうかな、何にしますか？
So, how should we take it? What should we do?
じゃあまずはね、こう、ハッ。いいね。満面の笑み、イエーイ！
First, let's do this—ha! Nice. Big smiles, yay!
取れた？取れた？取れた？じゃいっぱい撮ってあのハッシュタグでつぶやいてください。
Did you get it? Did you get it? Take lots of them and tweet with the hashtag!
おっしゃ、じゃあちょっと座ったりもしてみる？お、いいね、いいね。
Alright, shall we try sitting down too? Oh, nice, nice.
よし、よいしょ。おっ。おっ、おっ、おっ。
Okay, heave-ho. Oh, oh, oh.
ねー。うー。
Yeah... woo.
じゃ、じゃん、じゃん。乾杯！乾杯！乾杯！
Ta-da, ta-da! Cheers! Cheers! Cheers!
んなが、お二人さんもなんかしたいポーズとかあります？
Do you two have any poses you'd like to do?
したいポーズか。どうしようかな。
Pose we want to do? What should we do?
あ、じゃあ、じゃあポーズじゃないんだけど、一列に並んで、ちょっとこれ
Ah, well, not really a pose, but let's line up and... this...
あ、そうそう、ノエルちゃん先頭にしてさ。
Ah, right, with Noel-chan at the front.
あ、じゃあ、はいはい。
Ah, okay, okay, okay.
じゃ、ラミィちゃん真ん中入ってもらって。ありがとうございます。はい。
Then Lamy-chan in the middle. Thank you! Yes.
ええと、どっちか。ノエルちゃんから。
Um, which way? Starting from Noel-chan.
こうだね。
Like this.
そうだね。
That's right.
はい！わーわーわーわー！酒飲み組だよー！当たる？当たるかな？当たるいい感じとか出て一回点検してポーズ。
Yay! Wah-wah-wah! It's the sake-drinking group! Are we hitting each other? Will it hit? Let's check and pose.
どこだ？どこだ？
Where is it? Where is it?
こうか？こっちか？こうか？こう！オッケーオッケーオッケー！あ、ストップ！あ、こうか？あ、かわいいかわいい！
Like this? This way? Like this? Like this! Okay, okay, okay! Ah, stop! Ah, like this? Ah, cute, cute!
はい、かわいい！ありがとうございました！
Yes, cute! Thank you very much!
いいですね。団長先頭なのにね、ちょっと見えてなかったからね。
That's great. Even though the leader was at the front, she wasn't visible.
助かります。よし。
Good grief. Alright.
ラミィちゃんは？
How about Lamy-chan?
ああ、ラミィはやっぱりちょっとあれですかね、最後に寝たやつ？ちょっとね、ひきぎみとかね、なんか取れたらいいななんて思うんですけど。
Ah, for Lamy, I guess the one who fell asleep at the end? If we could get something like a slightly reserved one...
じゃあちょっとあれやろうね。みんなちょっと酔っ払って
Then let's do that. Everyone's a bit drunk...
では、失礼して。酔っ払っての。飲みすぎてさ、紅葉の真ん中で
Excuse me. Being drunk from drinking too much, in the middle of the autumn leaves...
おいしかったな、今日のお酒も。あー！最高だ！いっぱい飲もう！
Today's sake was delicious too. Ah, amazing! Let's drink a lot!
夢の中でも飲む。
Drinking even in our dreams.
うまいな。
So good.
体に良く染み込むよ、このポーズは。あたーる。
It soaks right into the body, this pose. Hits the spot.
なんか眠くなってきたね。
I'm getting kind of sleepy.
おやすみなさい。
Good night.
うん、寝るか。おやすみ。
Yeah, time for bed. Good night.
みんな、ありがと、おやすみ！いや、夢の中でライブ続きます！よろしくおねがいします！
Everyone, thanks, good night! The live continues in our dreams! Please look forward to it!
おやすみ。おやすみ。
Good night. Good night.
悪霊退散 悪霊退散 陰陽師物の怪困った時は
Evil spirits begone, evil spirits begone! Onmyoji, when monsters cause trouble,
どう万聖万同万聖万同 すぐり呼びましょう 陰陽師出撃だ！
Doman-seiman, Doman-seiman! Call them right away, Onmyoji, sortie!
イェイ！イェイ！
Yay! Yay!
イェイ！イェイ！イェイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
下弦の月が霧に揺れる
The waning moon shakes in the mist,
夜を包む塒雲
night's roosting clouds enfold it.
躓かれた番い雛 絡まれる非情の罠
A pair of crucified dolls caught in a cruel trap.
呻呼 今も燻る 思い胸に錆と宿らば
Ah, if only the feelings smoking in my heart would stay as rust...
水の様に優しく 花の様に劇しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
宿命らされた涙を 瞳の奥閉ざしても
Even if you lock away the tears dealt by fate deep in your eyes,
貴方を瞼が記憶しているの
your eyelids still remember you.
悪霊退散 悪霊退散
Evil spirits begone, evil spirits begone!
妖怪怪異お巡り困った時は
When troubled by specters and monsters,
ドーマンセーマン ドーマンセーマン
Doman Seman, Doman Seman!
助けてもらおう 苗字で使う
Ask for help, use your surname!
無明の淵で終焉を待つ
Waiting for the end in the dark abyss,
私は塒む身無し児
I am a homeless orphan.
踏み躙られた尽きる恋を 両手に包んだ壜
A bottle cradling trampled, exhausted love in both hands.
もう吝めない 共に辿る 冥みの黄泉路を
No longer stingy, let's walk the dark path of the underworld together.
水の様に優しく 花の様に劇しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
宿命らされた涙を 瞳の奥閉ざしても
Even if you lock away the tears dealt by fate deep in your eyes,
流れる血潮 止められない
you cannot stop the blood that flows!
悪霊退散 悪霊退散
Evil spirits begone, evil spirits begone!
怨霊縁起 困った時は
When troubled by vengeful spirits,
ドーマンセーマン ドーマンセーマン
Doman Seman, Doman Seman!
沈めてもらおう 苗字で使う
Put them to rest, use your surname!
辛い時 楽しい時
In painful times, in joyful times,
さぁそんな時 ここぞと月に闇が来る
now, at such times, darkness comes to the moon when needed!
その心の闇に 魔物達ぞ容赦なく入り込んで
Into that darkness of the heart, monsters mercilessly break in...
来るのだ！
and come!
だから 苦しくても挫けるな
Therefore, even if it hurts, don't break down!
落ち込むな 供養供養するな
Don't get depressed, don't offer memorial services!
何事にも屈しない 狂人な心こそは
A mad heart that yields to nothing
最強の武器なのだから！
is the ultimate weapon!
水の様に優しく 花の様に劇しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
宿命らされた涙を 瞳の奥閉ざしても
Even if you lock away the tears dealt by fate deep in your eyes,
狙うものは 内側にだけ
what you aim for is only within...
悪霊退散 頂上現象困った時は
Evil spirits begone, when troubled by supernatural phenomena,
ドーマンセーマン ドーマンセーマン
Doman Seman, Doman Seman!
払ってもらおう 苗字でLet's go!
Have them exorcised, use your surname, let's go!
悪霊退散 悪霊退散 呪いのわら人形
Evil spirits begone, a cursed straw doll...
困った時は ドーマンセーマン ドーマンセーマン
when troubled, Doman Seman, Doman Seman!
相談しましょう 苗字でLet's go!
Let's consult, use your surname, let's go!
やっぱり頼れる 苗字でLet's go!
As expected, we can rely on our surnames, let's go!
成仏しろよ～
Rest in peace!
さぁチェックラ～！
Now, check it out!
感情来ちゃいました！
The emotions have arrived!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
最強の二人きっちぇえ！
The strongest duo is awesome!
このライブの…
This live concert's...
初めてなんですね。ちょっと緊張しちゃいます。
This is my first time, so I'm a bit nervous.
こっちにしましょう、団長！
Let's go this way, Danchou!
ふっ、ぴっ、いやでも身長やっぱ
Hmph, phew—well, but height-wise, after all,
会長、威厳があるな。
Kaichou, you look so dignified.
高めこう、威厳をね。
Keeping it high... with dignity, you know.
団長も威厳を、威厳ですねえ。
Danchou also has dignity... very dignified.
誰が威厳ですねえ！
Who's dignified?!
いやだんちょーなん、会長！
I mean, Danchou... Kaichou!
まさかこんなとこに呼んでいただけるなんて、ありがとうございます。
To think you'd invite me to a place like this, thank you so much.
いやいやいや。
No, no, no.
だって約束したじゃん、覚えてる？覚えてる？
We promised, you know? Remember? Remember?
あ、あのもうあれですよね、あの
Ah, well, that's... you know, the...
歌枠の時に、あの
singing stream where, um,
のびしろ組の、のびしろ組ですからね、私達。
We're part of the 'Nobishiro-gumi', right, the growth group.
いや、のびしろの時に、あんときに歌えなかった曲があったんだよね。
Yeah, back in the Nobishiro stream, there was a song we couldn't sing.
そう、それが
Yeah, and that was...
今回歌った「Let's Go Million♪」イェイ！
The song we just performed: 'Let's Go Million♪' Yay!
いや、やりたかったんすよ、だんちょーと。
Yeah, I really wanted to do it with Danchou.
いやでもやっぱ3Dでね、やりたいからさ。
Yeah, but since we wanted to do it in 3D,
本当によかった今日。ドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥッ、イェイ！イェイ！いや、めっっちゃ楽しかったず！
it was truly great today. Du-du-du-du-du, yay! Yay! Man, it was suuuuper fun!
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much.
いやいやいやいや。でもあれだね、ちょっと
No, no, no, no. But you know, sort of...
2人でこうやって並ぶのも最初で最後になりますからね。そうですねえ。
Well, standing side by side like this is going to be the first and last time. That's true.
いっぱいに写真を撮ってくれるとうれしいよ。ぴぴぴの、のびしろ、のびしろコラボ。
We'd be so happy if you take lots of photos. Pipipi, Nobishiro, Nobishiro collab.
もうのびち、あののびち、あ、もうのびち、あのびおんびおん、あもうびおんびおんに
Nobichi, um Nobichi, ah, Nobichi, um, bion-bion, ah, bion-bion...
え、ここ会長どういう感じ？ちょっと動きをね伝授したい、あ伝授してもらいたいな。
So Kaichou, what's the vibe? I want you to teach me some movements... I mean, I'd love for you to teach me.
そう、団長ね、いつもなんか、なんかこうこういうポーズばっかしてるから、そう、団長、そう、まっすぐポーズしかないから。
Yeah, Danchou always does poses like this, right? Danchou only has straight-up poses.
そう、ここからでもね、やっぱ腰の動き一つでセクシーになるんです。腰の動きか！なるほど！
Right, but even from here, just a movement of the waist makes it sexy. Waist movement! I see!
そう、腰をね、まずはやっぱこう、腰をね、全体的に前にぴっ、あ、前にぴっ。なるほど。
Yeah, your waist... first, you know, pop your waist forward like this. Pop it forward. I see.
ぷいっ、ぷいっ。
Pui, pui.
ぐりゅるっと横にね。あ、ぐれぐるっと。
And swivel it to the side. Ah, swivel it.
そうです。あ、なるほど。腰がボールか。
That's right. Oh, I see. Your waist is like a ball.
いいです。あ、会長っぽい！いいですねえ！
Nice! It's very Kaichou-like! That's great!
その動きをね、あの、あでものびしろですね、ちょっと筋肉感ありすぎますね。ちょっと脳筋て
That movement... wait, it's Nobishiro, but there's too much muscle feel. Too muscle-brained...
いや、まだか、まだか、まだ書きが足りません。え、これ違う？おじさんのハズステのエアロビクスじゃないですか。やめてくださいよ。
No, wait, not yet, not enough writing. Wait, is this wrong? Isn't this an old guy's weird aerobics? Stop it.
いやでも画面のみんなもね、ぜひぜひこれやって、一緒にエコ、いや難しいな。
Well, but everyone on screen too, please definitely try doing this together... man, this is hard.
あでも、いいっすよ。いいっすか？イエス、団長、のびしろです！のびしろイェイ！
Ah, but that's good. Really? Yes, Danchou, it's Nobishiro! Nobishiro yay!
え、でもちょっと待って、団長とさ、なんかあれだな、さっき歌うときぴょーんってして、ぴょん、ぴょん、ぴょん、あ！
Wait, Danchou and I... when we were singing earlier, we went pyon, pyon, pyon, ah!
ヒップの位置が全然違いすぎるんだよな、さっき、ヒップが、やっぱでかいもんで、失礼します。失礼します。重たい！
Our hip positions are way too different. Earlier, my hips... since they're huge, excuse me. Excuse me. So heavy!
あーん、尻尾も付いてるんだよね。ね、尻尾、あ、尻尾もね
Ah, I have a tail too. Right, a tail, ah, the tail too...
あ、なんか団長、あれなんか記憶で、あれ、のすか？なんかこの尻尾、触ってもいい？
Ah, Danchou, do you remember... can I touch this tail?
あ、いいっすよ。全然、全然いいっすよ。触っていいですよ。あ、ちょっと、ちょっと待って、ちょっちょっちょっちょっ、危ない危ない危ない危ない！
Sure, go ahead. Totally fine. You can touch it. Ah, wait, wait, wait, wait! Dangerous, dangerous!
ドラゴンの世界でも幸せになろう！
Let's find happiness even in the dragon's world!
わいわいわいわいわいわいわい！
Yay yay yay yay yay yay yay!
団長でした！
That was Danchou!
ということで、皆さん一緒にチェンジしました！
So, everyone, we changed together!
ちょっとね、さっきCoco会長をボコボコ、ボコ回したからね、ちょっと会長リスペクト！そうリスペクトで、あの「わいわいわい」って入ってきました。
Since I beat up Kaichou earlier, as a sign of respect to Kaichou, I came in with 'Wai-wai-wai'.
どうも団長です。どう？どう？
Hello, it's Danchou. How is it? How is it?
かわいいでしょ。結構ね、やっぱ最近、ま、3D配信団長の枠では
Isn't it cute? Lately, in Danchou's 3D streams,
ないけど、この前フレアとね歌ったりとかで、この衣装の見覚えがあるんじゃないかなと。思います、可愛いしょ？
though not usually, I sang with Flare recently, so you might recognize this outfit. Don't you think it's cute?
団長ね、ほら！わ、脇が、ちょちょちょちょ、そんなに近づかれると、恥ずかしいなと
Danchou, look! My armpits—wait, wait, if you get this close, I feel kind of embarrassed,
思うんですが、ちょっと普段の服は結構
I think, but my usual clothes are pretty...
そうだね、あの着物もそうだし、通常衣装もそうだし、私服も全部脇が見えないので、脇が見えるのはとても
That's right, my kimono, regular outfit, and casual clothes all hide my armpits, so being able to see my armpits is very...
貴重です。背中もちょっと見える。ぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐる、ね？見えます。
precious. You can see a bit of my back too. Round and round and round, see? You can see it.
お兄層はね、ま、いつものお兄層なので、いっぱい写真撮って、あのハッシュタグでいっぱい呟いてくれるとうれしいです。よろしくお願いします。
Nisou is always nisou, so I'd be so happy if you take lots of photos and tweet them with the hashtag. Thank you!
えどうしようかな、なんかせっかくだからアイドルっぽいポーズ
What should I do? Since it's a rare chance, an idol-like pose...
なんかね、さっき「ワイワイワイワイ」とかさ、なんか、あのさっきの曲が、もちろんね、アイドル、もう素晴らしいアイドルだったけど、二人ともね、ちょっと王道のアイドルじゃなかったなと思うから、ちょっと、アイドルっほ、あ、それこそあれか、この見守り、これね、あの記念の
Like, earlier with 'Wai-wai-wai' and stuff... the previous song, of course, was an amazing idol song, but neither of us felt like orthodox idols, so I thought, wait, speaking of idol-ness, this mamomori, this commemorative...
100万人記念突破っ 突破した時のあのサムネイルで
For the thumbnail when we reached 1 million subscribers,
いや、これ、これやろうかな、これって
I was wondering if I should do this pose...
こんな感じか？ いや、いいんじゃないの？
Something like this? Well, isn't it good?
こういう感じ 指をこう近づけて
Like this, bringing your fingers close together like this—
あ、カメラ、カメラマンさんありがとうございます。
Ah, camera, cameraman-san, thank you very much!
こういう感じで、身長158cmだからね、ちょっと小さいんだよね。
Like this... since I'm 158 cm tall, I'm a bit short, you see.
小さいから団員さんの目線的にはもしかして、こんぐらいになったりするのかな？
Because I'm short, from the Danin's perspective, do you end up looking down like this?
いや、でも団長の、あれかな、ちょっと団長の団員さ、あ、で、あ、ぼーや、よしよし、あら、かわいいね。
Well, but Danchou's... ah, boy, there there, oh, how cute.
え、どうしたの？今日暇なの？あとからね、団長ライブ終わったあと、ちょっと、あの、一緒に遊ぼうかっていうね、そうそう。
Eh, what's wrong? Are you free today? Later, after the live ends, we'll play together...
これ、あの、大空警察に見られてるとちょっと団長、捕まっちゃうんだよね。
If Oozora Police sees this, Danchou might get arrested, you know.
ま、こういう色々と写真撮って、あと、ま、ふりふりとかね、アイドル、アイドル、あ、でもせっかく
Well, taking various photos like this, and frills too... idols! But since we're here,
だから、ここ会長、いやなんか懐かしいな、ここ会長にそのポーズをなんか伝授してもらった時があって、
Coco-kaichou... ah, it brings back memories. Coco-kaichou once taught me this pose,
そん時がすごいガニ股ポーズがめちゃくちゃ可愛いアイドルとしてやっぱガニ股だよねって言ってたから
and she said that a wide-leg pose is super cute for an idol, so...
ちょっとから、ちょっとガニ股、せっかくだからね、ウィッ。
Since it's special, let's do the wide-leg pose!
ちょっと普段の団長ではない感じのポーズもいいんじゃないかなって。あ、腰ね、あ、そうそう、腰の、腰突きも
A pose unlike the usual Danchou might be nice too. Ah, and the hip thrusts...
教えてもらったから。でもこの腰突きすると、なんか団長的に夢見る空を思い出すんだよね。チュン、チュン、チュンチュンチュン。
she taught me that too. But doing these hip thrusts reminds me of "Yumemiru Sora".
いや、そんな感じで、お前、いつ歌うんだよって、思いましたか？団長、もちろんこの衣装になったからには、アイドルソングを歌いたいと思います！
So anyway, did you think "When is she going to sing?" Well, now that I'm in this outfit, I definitely want to sing an idol song!
いや、ちょっとこのアイドル衣装でね、歌うのはちょっと、ま、みんなはね聞いたことあるし、団長が踊ってんのも見たことある感じなきがするんですけど、この衣装では初めてなので、ぜひ聞いていてください。
Singing in this idol outfit... everyone has probably heard it before, and seen me dance, but it's my first time in this outfit, so please listen!
では、いきます。ドキッ！こういうのが恋なの？
Now then, here we go. "Doki! Kouiu no ga Koi na no?"!
やっぱり恋はキラキラ
Love is always sparkling,
ドキドキしてしまうな
making my heart beat fast.
この出会い奇跡だ
This meeting is a miracle.
他には何もいらない
I don't need anything else,
君を見てる
I'm just looking at you.
星の見えない夜は探してしまう 君の瞳輝く光
On nights when stars can't be seen, I search for the shining light in your eyes.
誰より今会いたい人がいる
There is someone I want to see right now more than anyone.
退屈な夜を終わらせにきて
Come and put an end to this boring night.
明日には会える わかってる
I know we'll meet tomorrow.
話したいことばかりだよ
There are so many things I want to talk about.
君と同じ時間を過ごすことが何より大事なの
Spending the same time with you is more important than anything.
やっぱり恋はキラキラ
Love is always sparkling,
ドキドキしてしまうな
making my heart beat fast.
夢なら覚めないで
If this is a dream, please don't wake me up.
甘い春の風に吹かれて 心がときめいてる
Fanned by the sweet spring breeze, my heart is fluttering.
きっと恋する人の数だけ世界は
Surely, the world spins around and around
グルグルと回るんだ
as many times as there are people in love.
切ないほど君の声音に耳を澄ませ
I strain my ears to hear your voice, so painful yet dear.
君の名前書いて恥ずかしくなる
Writing your name makes me feel embarrassed,
慌てて隠した ノートの端
hurriedly hiding it in the corner of my notebook.
きっと忘れない これから起こることは ひとつひとつ思い出になる
I will surely never forget everything from now on, each moment becoming a memory.
心はいつでも空回り 上手くいかないけれども
My heart always spins its wheels and things don't go well,
君のはじけるような笑顔だけをずっと見ていたい
but I just want to see your bursting smile forever.
そうだ恋はメラメラ
That's right, love burns fiercely,
燃えて熱くなれ
getting hotter and hotter.
この想い消さないで
Don't let this feeling fade away.
君と見る景色はもう 何だって輝いてる
The scenery I see with you shines no matter what.
きっと君を想って流す涙なら それすら愛おしくて
Surely, even the tears I shed thinking of you are so dear.
ハロ 窓を開けて 小さく呟いた
Hello, I opened the window and muttered softly.
ハロワユ 誰もいない 部屋で一人
How are you, all alone in an empty room.
モーニン 朝が来たよ 土砂降りの朝が
Morning has come, a pouring morning.
ティクタク 私のネジ 誰か巻いて
Tick-tock, someone wind up my spring.
窓を開けて 小さく呟いた
Opening the window, I murmured softly
誰もいない 部屋で一人
In a room where no one else is around
朝が来たよ 土砂降りの朝が
Morning has come, a pouring rain morning
私のネジを 誰か巻いて
Could someone please wind up my spring?
昔のアニメにそんなのいたっけな
Why was there someone like that in old anime?
羨ましいな 皆に愛されて
I'm envious, being loved by everyone
馬鹿な事言わないでで支度をしなくちゃ
Don't say stupid things, stop making a fuss
涙の跡を隠すため
To hide the traces of my tears,
もう口癖になった「まあいっか」
"Oh well" became my favorite phrase
昨日の言葉がふと頭をよぎる
Yesterday's words suddenly crossed my mind
「もう君には全然期待してないから」
"I have no expectations for you anymore."
そりゃまあ私だって自分に期待などしてないけれど
Well, I don't expect much of myself either,
アレ一体どういうつもりですか
But what on earth was that supposed to mean?
喉元まで出かかった言葉
The words that almost reached my throat,
口をついて出たのは嘘
what slipped out of my mouth was a lie
こうして今日も私は貴重な言葉を浪費して生きていく
And so today, once again, I waste precious words as I live on
何故隠してしまうのですか
Why do I always hide it?
笑われるのが怖いのですか
Is it because I'm afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか
Is it because I don't want to see anyone?
それ本当ですか
Is that the truth?
曖昧という名の海に溺れて
Drowning in a sea called ambiguity,
息も出来ないほど苦しいの
it's so painful I can barely breathe
少し声が聞きたくなりました 本当に弱いな
I wanted to hear a voice, even just a little, I'm truly weak
一向に進まない支度の中途 朧げな頭で思う
Not moving forward, stuck halfway, I think with a hazy head:
「もう理由を付けて休んでしまおうかな」
"Should I just find a reason and take a break?"
いやいや分かってますって 何となく言ってみただけだよ
No, no, I know, I was just saying that for no reason
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I know, so don't get mad at me
幸せだろうと 不幸だろうと 平等に 残酷に 朝日は昇る
Whether you're happy or unhappy, the morning sun rises equally and cruelly
生きているだけで精一杯の私に これ以上何を望むというの
For me, just trying to live is exhausting, what more could you want from me?
何故気にしてしまうのですか
Why do I always care so much?
本当は愛されたいのですか
Do you actually want to be loved?
その手を離したのは誰ですか
Who was it that let go of that hand?
気が付いていますか
Do you realize it?
人生にタイムカードがあるなら 終わりの時間は何時なんだろう
If life has a time card, what time is the end?
私が生きた分の給料は 誰が払うんですか
Who pays the salary for the time I've lived?
サンキュー ありがとって言いたい野
"Thank you," I want to say
サンキュー ありがとって言いたいよ
サンキュー 一度だけでも良いから
"Thank you," even if it's just once,
心の底から大泣きしながら ありがとって言いたいよ
I want to cry my eyes out from the bottom of my heart and say thank you
サンキュー ありがとって言いたいよ
Thank you, thank you.
サンキュー 一度だけでも良いから
Thank you, even if it's just once,
心の底から大泣きしながら ありがとって言いたいよ
I want to cry my eyes out from the bottom of my heart and say thank you
何故隠してしまうのですか
Why do you keep it hidden?
本当は聞いて欲しいのですか
Do you actually want me to listen?
絶対に笑ったりしないから 話してみませんか
I'll never laugh, so won't you talk to me?
口を開けなければ分からない
You won't know unless you open your mouth,
思っているだけでは伝わらない
just thinking won't get it across
なんてめんどくさい生き物でしょう 人間というのは
What a troublesome creature humans are
ハロ ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
あなたに ハロ ハワユ
For now, I'll say hello, how are you?
あれ？なんか…あ、なんか音声が聞こえてきたな。
Huh? Wait... Ah, I can hear some audio coming through.
あれ？
Huh?
聞こえ…が、がんばれ！ちょっと引っ込んでくるね。
Can you... Hang in there! I'll step back for a bit.
ちょっと…うわっ！離してよ！
Wait... Whoa! Let go of me!
どっこい、どっこい、どっこい！もう…出なくていいんじゃない？
Heave-ho, heave-ho! You don't really need to come out, do you?
いやいやいやいや！
No, no, no, no!
だって、ノエルちゃ…すごく良かったよ。
But Noel, you... did really great.
本当に？でも
Really? But...
さっきさ、ほらほらリハーサルのときにさ、ほら、
Earlier during rehearsals, you know, when—
団長がね、「あー、だった、だった」ってなったときに、フレアが「えー、みたいな、ちょっと入れる」って言ってて、ガチでさ、き、きいてくれてたんでしょ？
Dancho went "Ah, that's right," Flare said, "Ehh, like this, adding a little bit," and you were seriously listening, right?
ちょ、ちょ、よかった！いや、
Aw, that's great! No—
嬉しんだけど、この
I'm happy, but this...
スルイ可愛いから。もうこの後ずっとソロでエンチャ…
Thru-i is so cute. After this, you're doing solo encoring...
いやいや、そんなこと…
No, no, nothing like that!
今日はね、フレアがね、来てくれましたよ、みんな！
Today, Flare came to support us, everyone!
どうも！いつもノエルがお世話になってます！
Hello everyone! Noel is always in your care!
そう、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
え、どういう旦那さんつうか、今日どういう…どういう感じ？どういう感じ？
Eh, what kind of husband-and-wife vibe is this today? What kind of vibe?
えー、じゃあ今日は、あの旦那さんに、まあ旦那は譲るとして、私は親友っていう形で今日は。
Uh, so today, well, I'll let him be the husband, and I'll be the best friend today.
ああなんか、親友、親友？
Oh, like best friends, best friends?
なんかちょっと、あ、変わった、なんか違う、なんか扉が開きそう、ピーン。
It's like, oh, it's different, like a door is about to open, *ping*.
じゃあ私たち、あの二人、あの、一番中の親友ってこと、あ、この後ちょっと二人でずらっとなるかも…
Then the two of us, you know, being best friends in the inner circle... ah, after this we might get a bit out of sync...
ちょっとそれ言うとね、それ言うと私たち、いやー、来てくれてありがとう！
If you say that, well, if you say that, we... Man, thanks for coming!
じゃあ、あれだね、ちょっとさ、団長あれ歌う？
So, speaking of that, Dancho, are you going to sing that?
え、ネタ、あ、あ、そのレッツゴーオミオジ…そういう…
Eh, material— ah, ah, that Let's Go Omi-oji... that kind of...
今の流れがやっぱり、なんかちょっとネタ感…
The flow right now feels a bit like a joke...
フレアさん、我々歌った曲あるじゃないですか。
Flare-san, there's a song we sang, right?
なんかだったっけ？
What was it again?
歌な、歌って、歌って、思い出して、なんか歌ったっけ？
Sing, sing, sing, remember, what did we sing?
ということで、聴いてください！
So with that, please listen!
いい？じゃあみんな、まあ、わかると思うけど、聴いてください、ナイショの話。
Ready? Everyone probably knows, but please listen, "Naisho no Hanashi."
今日も元気な目覚ましが
Today, a cheerful alarm clock
あたしの脳に朝を告げる
tells my brain that morning has come
寝ぼけ眼をこすったら
When I rub my sleepy eyes,
一日が始まるわ
a day begins
机の上に置いたまま
Leaving it on my desk,
忘れ物を今日もまたしてる
I've forgotten something again today
全力疾走で追いかけた
I chased after you at full sprint,
どうして気が付かないかな
why didn't you notice?
ずっとあたしがこのままで
Don't think that I'll stay
いるなんて思わないでよ
like this forever
きっといつかどこかの誰かが
I'm sure that someday, someone somewhere
あたしのこともらってしまうのわかってるの？
will take me away, do you understand that?
その時になったって遅いんだから
If it comes to that point, it'll be too late
その時に泣いたって知らないんだから
If you cry at that time, I won't care anymore
そんな顔したってだめなんだから
Even if you make that kind of face, it's no use
really, you are so mean
ちょっとびっくりどきっしたんじゃないっ！？
Weren't you a little startled!?
さっきからあの制服の子が気になってんのバレバレだわ
It's so obvious that you've been paying attention to that girl in uniform since earlier
あたしが隣にいるのにそれってどういうつもりなの
Even though I'm right beside you, what do you mean by that?
なににも言わないでいいから
You don't need to say anything at all,
あたしのことを一番に大切にしてよ
just treasure me above all else
なのにあなたはいっつもそうやってさ
Yet you're always acting like that, no matter when
鈍感なの？わざとなの？
Are you dense? Or are you doing it on purpose?
いまさら気付いたって遅いんだから
Even if you realize it now, it's too late
いまさら言い訳したって知らないんだから
Even if you make excuses now, I won't care anymore
そんな顔したってだめなんだから
Even if you make that kind of face, it's no use
really, you are easy
怒りたくなるわyou know？
It makes me want to get mad, you know?
その時になるまで見ていてよね
Keep watching me until that moment comes
その時になったら泣いちゃうかもね
If that moment comes, I might cry
そんな顔しちゃったらだめかもです
If you make that kind of face, it might be no good
really, i love you
だけどナイショの話
But it's a secret story
その時になったって遅いんだから
If it comes to that point, it'll be too late
その時に泣いたって知らないんだから
If you cry at that time, I won't care anymore
そんな顔したってだめなんだから
Even if you make that kind of face, it's no use
でもね
But you know,
その時になるまで見ていてよね
Watch over me until that time comes,
その時になったら泣いちゃうかもね
I might end up crying when that time comes.
そんな顔しちゃったらダメかもですね
It might not be good if you make that kind of face.
リアリュ、リアリュだけどナイショの話
Really, really, but this is a secret between us.
その時になったって遅いんだから
It'll be too late by the time that happens.
その時になったって泣いたりしないんだから
I won't care if you cry by then.
そんな顔したってダメなんだから
Making that kind of face won't work, you know.
でもね いつもサンキューって思ってたりして
But you know, I sometimes think, "Always, thank you."
ネグリジェとかの曲歌いたかった、ずっと歌いたかったね!
I wanted to sing a song like Negligee, I've always wanted to sing it!
歌いたかった、大好きだよ!
I wanted to sing it, I love it!
マリン船長じゃん!
It's Marine-senchou!
え、びっくりした、いつからいたの?
Eh, I was surprised, since when were you here?
え、今ここハートから生まれました あ、生まれたての子供だよ!
Eh, just now a heart was born here. Ah, I'm a newborn child!
大事にしてね! ちょっときついね!
Cherish me! This is a bit tough!
なんで来たと思う? え、なんで来てくれたの?
Why do you think I came? Eh, why did you come?
ノエルの100万人だから決まってるでしょ! えー嬉しい!
It's Noel's 1 million, so of course! Eh, I'm so happy!
嬉しい! ありがとー! 抱きつきたく...
So happy! Thank you! I want to hug you...
喧嘩やめな!
Stop fighting!
いや本当にありがとう二人ともね! 今日ね来てくれて本当にありがとう!
Seriously, thank you both so much! Thank you so much for coming today!
来たよ! 聞いた? 来たよ!
I came! Did you hear? I came!
なんで私んときはきつい言うの!
Why do you say it's tough when it's me?!
帰ろうかな? いや帰んないで!帰んないで!
Should I go home? No, don't go home! Don't go home!
いややっぱね、せっかく三人揃ったからにはさ、やっぱ写真撮影とかしたくないですか?
Well, since the three of us are finally together, wouldn't you want to take a photo or something?
ええーー!どうしよっかな?
Eeh?! What should I do?
なんで? なんのノリは... でもしたいね!
Why? What's with that reaction... But I want to do it!
でもあれかな、でもその前に、僕今日歌だから... あ! あ! あ!
But you know, before that, since I have a song today... Ah! Ah! Ah!
ちょ写真撮影の前に歌気になっちゃう感じですか?
Ah, before taking photos, are you curious about the song?
お腹... なんかトレンドうんぬんとかはやてた気がしたけど
My stomach... I felt like trends and stuff were trending, but
ああー! なんかネタ歌? ネタじゃな...
Aaah! Some gag song? It's not a gag...
見えなかった! 気のせい?
I couldn't see it! Was it my imagination?
気のせいかな? 見逃した可能性あったりも... ど、どれどれ?
Maybe my imagination? Might have missed it... Wh-which one?
一番胴体視力の高い私に任せてください!
Leave it to me, the one with the highest dynamic visual acuity!
え? どれどれ?
Eh? Which one? Which one?
あ、2か? お、2え? やった! やった!
Ah, 2? Oh, 2? Yay! Yay!
遅いじゃない! 2だよ! え、これ!
Not slow! It's 2! Eh, this!
おおがいわーい! これ来たら...
Yay! When this comes...
でもすげえトレンド1位がでかすぎるからがっつ...でかすぎるわ、ちょっと
But the #1 trend is way too big... It's too big, wait.
2でもね、すごく嬉しいです! ありがとうね! ねえ!
Even with #2, I'm super happy! Thank you!
じゃあちょっとね、三人揃ったからにはちょっと、本当ね、歌いたい曲があって お!
Well then, since the three of us are together, there's a song we really want to sing. Oh!
あの、3期生といったらまずデビューした時歌枠、必ず歌った曲あったの覚えてる?
Um, speaking of the 3rd gen, do you remember the song we always sang in our debut singing streams?
え、何それ? 懐かしっ! 覚えてるよ!
Eh, what's that? Nostalgic! I remember!
覚えてるよね? 覚えてるよ!
You remember, right? I remember!
え、嘘! 覚えてる?
Eh, no way! You remember?
え、嘘だ! うそでしょ?
Eh, no way! You're kidding, right?
前も覚えてる! めっちゃ泣いてたじゃん、それ!
I remember before too! You were crying so much during that!
あれね! コメントでもね、分かってるって思うけど...
That! I think people knew in the comments too...
あれ、ピーピー泣いてたやつね! そう、それ! 誕生日ね、ちょっと...
Ah, the one where you were crying your eyes out! Yes, that! Birthday, well...
それはちょっと置いといて、ま、ちょっと三人でね、歌いたい曲があるので、皆さん聞いてください!
Let's put that aside for a moment. Well, since the three of us have a song we want to sing, everyone please listen!
それでは、聞いてください、「風になる」!
Without further ado, please listen to "Kaze ni Naru"!
忘れていた目を閉じて取り戻せ恋のうた
Close the forgotten eyes and retrieve the love song.
青空に隠れている手を伸ばしてもう一度
Reach out your hand hidden in the blue sky one more time.
忘れないですぐそばに僕がいるいつの日も
Don't forget, soon I'll be by your side all the time.
星空を眺めている一人きりの夜明けも
Even when at dawn you gaze at the starry sky alone.
忘れていた目を閉じて 取り戻せ 恋のうた
Close your forgotten eyes and bring back the love song.
青空に隠れている 手を伸ばしてもう一度
Reaching out once more to the blue sky hidden above.
忘れないですぐそばに 僕がいるいつの日も
Don't forget, I'm right by your side, always.
星空を眺めている 一人きりの夜明けも
Even on solitary dawns when you gaze at the starry sky.
たった一つの心 悲しみに暮れないで
Keep your one and only heart from sinking into sadness.
君のためいきなんて 春風に変えてやる
I'll turn all your sighs into a gentle spring breeze.
忘れていた窓開けて 走り出せ 恋のうた
Open the forgotten window and run out to the love song.
青空に託している 手をかざしてもう一度
Holding up your hand to the blue sky once more.
忘れないよ すぐそばに 君がいる いつの日も
Don't forget, you're right by my side, always.
陽のあたる坂道を 自転車で駆けのぼる
Riding my bicycle up the sunlit slope,
君と失くした思い出乗せて行くよ
carrying the memories I lost with you.
ラララララ 口ずさむ くちびるを染めて行く
Lalalalala, humming as it stains my lips.
君と見つけた幸せ 花のように
Like a flower is the happiness I found with you.
忘れていた窓開けて 走り出せ 恋のうた
Open the forgotten window and run out to the love song.
青空に託している 手をかざしてもう一度
Holding up your hand to the blue sky once more.
忘れないよ すぐそばに 君がいる いつの日も
Don't forget, you're right by my side, always.
星空に輝いている 涙揺れる明日も
Even on tomorrows when wavering tears shine in the starry sky.
たった一つの言葉 この胸に抱きしめて
Embracing that single word tightly in my chest.
君のため僕は今 春風に吹かれている
For your sake, I am now blown by the spring breeze.
陽のあたる坂道を 自転車で駆けのぼる
Riding my bicycle up the sunlit slope,
君と交わした約束乗せて行くよ
carrying the promise I made with you.
ラララララ 口ずさむ
Lalalalala, humming
くちびるを染めて行く
as it stains my lips.
君と誓った約束乗せて行くよ
Carrying the vow I swore with you,
ラララララ 口ずさむ
Lalalalala, humming
くちびるを染めて行く
as it stains my lips.
君と出会えた幸せ 祈るように
As if praying for the happiness of meeting you.
陽のあたる坂道を 自転車で駆けのぼる
Riding my bicycle up the sunlit slope,
君と誓った約束乗せて行くよ
carrying the vow I swore with you.
ラララララ 口ずさむ
Lalalalala, humming
くちびるを染めて行く
as it stains my lips.
君と出会えた幸せ 祈るように
As if praying for the happiness of meeting you.
楽しー！ハハハハッ！
So fun! Hahaha!
楽しかったね！
That was so much fun!
もうちょっとここにいよう？ あれ、どうしたの？
Let's stay here a bit longer? Huh, what's wrong?
帰ろま……あ、待って
Let's go ho— Ah, wait!
ここノエルのステージだから！
Hey, this is Noel's stage!
写真撮ろうよ！
Let's take a photo!
そう、写真撮ろうとしてたわ
Ah right, we were trying to take a photo.
みんなすごい拍手だよ、ありがとう！
Everyone is clapping so much, thank you!
ちょっと3人でさ、せっかくね、アイドル衣装だからさ、写真撮りたいな！
Since the three of us are in idol outfits, let's take a photo!
え、どんな写真撮る？おっぱいの大きさでも比べる？
What kind of photo? Compare boob sizes?
え、そんな舐めるように…ちょっと…揉むじゃん
Hey, don't look at it like that... massaging it...
結構ね、難しいね、これね。
It's pretty difficult, isn't it?
あまり見ないで、これ。
Don't look too closely at this.
ちゃんとしろ。え？にやにやが。え？
Act properly. Eh? You're grinning. Eh?
今日は、よう持っておる。
Today, you're holding up well.
持ってるね。
You are, aren't you?
なんか入ってんの？
Is something in there?
ば、入れた！入れないで、やめてよ。
I-I put it in! Don't put it in, stop it.
入れてないよね？マリアオーケーでしょ。
You didn't put anything in, right? Marine's okay, right?
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
では、ちょっとどれかな？
Now, let's see which one...
あ、もうもしかして。
Ah, could it be...
もしかして？
Could it be?
あともうちょっと撮れるって言って。
They said we can film a bit more.
本当？もっと撮れるの？
Really? We can film more?
じゃあちょっと、どうしようかな？ない撮ろうかな？
Then what should we do? What kind of pose should we take?
じゃあ二ポーズ撮るって？
Two poses?
二ポーズ？何が？コメント。じゃあ一ポーズは、私たちが決めよう。うんと。
Two poses? What? Comments. Then we'll decide on one pose. Um...
じゃあどうしようかな？どうする？
So what should we do? What do you think?
いいのそれで任せて本当。
Is that fine? Just leave it to me, really.
ちゃんじゃあやっぱコメントでも拾いたいから。
But I want to pick up comments too.
コメント見てる。
I'm reading comments.
見てる。コメント？コメント見てるポーズ。
I see. Comments? The pose for reading comments.
なるほど。船長、頭大きい？
I see. Captain, is your head big?
え？ちょっとこの辺に立とうかな。あー。
Eh? Let's stand around here. Ah—
いやー、小顔。なんか、年、女の、女特有の。
Man, small face. And that unique women's...
どっちのがする？
Which one do you do?
いいよ。お姉さんの方ね。どっちすの？
Sure. The older sister's style. Which one are you doing?
なんかフレアかっこいい。
Flare looks cool.
なんかフレア可愛い。じゃあ後ろだから真ん中どうぞ。
Flare looks cute. Well, it's the back, so go to the middle.
あ、よ、俺はと。
Ah, yo, I am...
え、おい、かぶってるじゃん。もう、本当ありがとうございます、お二人とも。
Eh, oi, you're covering me. Seriously, thank you both so much.
もうちょっとここにいる。
Stay right here a bit longer.
じゃあ手繋いで帰ろうね、みんな。
Let's hold hands and go back, everyone.
え？手繋ぐ？手繋ぐ？なんで？なんで？
Eh? Hold hands? Hold hands? Why? Why?
じゃあな。
See ya.
後から、後からね。後からよろしくね。
Later on, later. Take care of me later.
なんかじゃあ二人でてぇてぇする前に、
Before those two have their sweet moment,
でも団長はね、あの団員さん本当今日は100万人記念3Dライブ見てくれて、ありがとうございます。
but as for Danchou, I really want to thank all the Danchou-san for watching today's 1 million subscriber 3D live.
団長からね、実はあの、ちょっとね、お知らせがあるんですけど、いいですか？ちょっとね、お知らせ。
Actually, Danchou has a little announcement... is that alright? A little announcement.
いや、本当に団長ね、この度、なんとみんなびっくりすると思うんだけど、まあ、白金ノエル100万人記念ということで、
Seriously, Danchou... this time, everyone will probably be surprised, but for Shirogane Noel's 1 million subscriber commemoration,
今回なんと、グッ、グッズを出、出します！出しました！イエーイ！
this time, we are releasing—! We are releasing goods! We released them! Yay!
はい、なんとね、100万人記念ということで、
Yes, as a 1 million subscriber commemoration,
グッズを出させていただきました。手紙ももらえるの？
we are releasing goods. You also get a letter?
そう、そうなんですよ、ちょっと。手紙もあるんですけど、
Yes, that's right, so... There's also a letter, but
一個一個ね、ちょっと紹介させていただきたいと思います。じゃあちょっと、運営さん、いいですか？
I'd like to introduce them one by one. So management, is that okay?
よし、で、まず一つ目。
Alright, first of all, number one.
このわたお先生、団長のね、父親の描き下ろしのB2タペストリー。
This B2 tapestry illustrated by Watao-sensei, Danchou's "father."
これさ、見ての通り、なんと、3期生に団長祝われてるんですよ。
As you can see, Danchou is being celebrated by the 3rd gen.
なんで？祝われてるんですよ。ね、さっきね、ちょっと、まあ、あのマリンとかフレアも言ってたけど、なんかね、ちょっと大人っぽいよね。マリンフレア大人っぽくて、なんか、あのぺこるしがね、ちょっと幼い感じで、なんかね、すごい可愛い感じになってます。
We're being celebrated! Right, earlier Marine and Flare mentioned it too, but it looks a bit mature, right? Marine and Flare look mature, while Pekora and Rushia look a bit younger, giving it a really cute vibe.
はい、いや、本当に、ぜひぜひこちら、ゲットしてみてください。で、次いきます。
Yes, seriously, please definitely check this out and get it. Now, moving on to the next.
で、こちらが、100万人記念アクリルミラーパネルです。なるほど、この発想なかったね。
And this is the 1 million subscriber commemorative acrylic mirror panel. I see, I didn't think of this idea.
で、こちらね、どういうことかっていうと、団長ね、金たて届いたんですけど、ちょっと部屋がね、ちょっと汚くて、まだ金たてみんなに写真に載せてないんだけどね、金たて届いて、やっぱね、団長だけでもなくて、団員さんにもやっぱ金たてっぽい、そういうさ、100万人っていう証というのをね、やっぱり一緒に飾りたいなと思って、あのこちらアクリルミラーパネル、はい、
And, what does this mean? Danchou received the gold plaque, but my room is a bit messy so I haven't posted a picture of the gold plaque to everyone yet, but since the gold plaque arrived, I thought I'd want to display that proof of 1 million subscribers together with the Danchou-san, so we made this acrylic mirror panel, yes...
あの、発売、売るか、売るか。なんかすごい天の声が聞こえるけど、でも褒められてる気がする。ありがとうございます。では次行きますか、ぽい。
selling... selling? I hear the voice of the heavens, but I feel like I'm being praised. Thank you very much. Shall we go to the next, poi.
で、こちら、こちらね、あの朝活配信でもちょっと現地を取ったんだけど、どっちも欲しい。白黒？すごい、黒ちょっとギャル男だな。
And this one, we took photos during the Asakatsu stream too, but I want both. White and black? Wow, black is a bit like a gal-o.
今ね、男喋ってるからね。初めてのね、Tシャツを出しました！いや、すごいかっこいいでしょ。まあさっきのね、なんかちょっと天の声も言ってたけど、団長らしくその白銀聖騎士団の紋章を、あの、なんて言うんだろ、マークバーンって載せつつ、
I'm talking right now! We released our very first T-shirt! Isn't it super cool? Well, as the voice of the heavens mentioned earlier, putting the Shirogane Holy Knights emblem on it like *bam*, in a way that suits Danchou,
なんか普段使いもできるようなかっこいい感じになってます。白と黒で、あの、二色展開あるんですけど、今回、あの、さっきも出たように全部セットが、あるんですけど、全部セットを買ったらその団長のお手紙も付くんですが、そこね注意点が、あの、白と黒二種類あるので、あの、購入される方は、あの、間違いなくよろしくお願いします。なんならば二色とも買ってくれると嬉しいです！よろしくおねがいします！
it's designed to be cool enough for everyday use. There are two color variations in white and black, and as mentioned earlier, there's an all-in-one set, and if you buy the all-in-one set, Danchou's letter is included. Note that there are two types, white and black, so please make sure when purchasing. I'd be happy if you bought both colors! Thank you very much!
いや、本当にね、すごいおしゃれな感じになってるんですよ。みんな白と黒どっちも買ってください。本当ね、団長サンプルいただいたというか、サンプル見たんですけど、
Yeah, seriously, it looks super stylish. Everyone, please buy both white and black. Really, Danchou received a sample, well, I saw the sample...
どっちもね
Both of them are...
いい感じにカッチュイイ感じでね
Looking really cool in full armor, you know.
そう、ギャ、ギャルを
So, garu--
ちょっと手の声なんて言ったか忘れちゃったけど
Wait, what did I say just now?
ギャルでも切れる
Well, even with "gyaru," it's cool.
まあ、とにかく、ちょっとかっこいい感じになっているので
Anyway, it has a cool vibe,
ぜひぜひ来てくれると嬉しいです。
so please, please come check it out!
いや、本当にみんなにこの、まあ、本当にずっと前から
I'm really so happy that everyone can--
ちょっとこれをね、計画してて
Well, I've been planning this for a while,
やっとお知らせできたのがすごく嬉しいです。
and I'm so happy I can finally announce it.
このあとね、22時、22時から発売されるので、よろしくお願いいたします。
It'll be available starting at 22:00 today, so please look forward to it!
いやー
Man...
じゃあちょっと団長ね、まあ、ここで最後の曲になってしまうんですが
Well, chieftain, this will be our final song.
あの、皆様に、団員さんに感謝の気持ちを込めて、アイドルらしいのえちゃんを最後に見せたいと思います。
I want to show you a Noel-chan full of gratitude to all of you, true to her idol self.
それでは、感謝の気持ちを込めて歌わさせていただきます。
So, with all my gratitude, I'll sing it for you.
それでは聴いてください。「ファンサ」
Please listen to it. "Fansa."
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”
My repayment is a kiss with all my love!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting, you know?
♡作って恋にしちゃってください！
Please make a heart shape and fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I will do anything that can be done,
NGなしで体当たり挑戦
taking on challenges head-on with no restrictions.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti-comments found through ego-searching—
ふざけんな！…誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me! I understand that better than anyone else.
でも大丈夫 ステージに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand on this stage, everyone is here.
(いくよ！)
(Let's go!)
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(fooo!!)
My repayment is a kiss with all my love! (Fooo!!)
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでいて愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this special night filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write letters to me too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
It's still too early for scandals, but
裏切りません！宣誓しときます
I won't betray you! I declare it right now.
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment.
ふざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with pure ability.
だから辞めない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
That's why I won't quit, because I hate losing and I'm here.
こぶし上げて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fist! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めたmonaビームで”(fooo!!)
My repayment is "Mona Beam filled with love"! (Fooo!!)
大歓声！もっと！まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Louder cheers! More! Come on, more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めたわがままソング
Accept my selfish song filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is approaching, it's so lonely.
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though I'm having fun, I feel like crying.
次も次もまた会えるよね？
We'll meet again next time and the next time too, right?
(やくそく！)
(Promise!)
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
even the heartless words of someone
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強くなろう
are necessary, are necessary. Let's become stronger!
好きに叫ぶ！もっと！楽しんじゃお！もっと！
Scream out your love! More! Enjoy yourself to the fullest! More!
忘れないで 特別な日にできますように
Don't forget, so that it becomes a special day.
共にうたおうずっと！共にあゆもうずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
あいことばはとびっきりのl・o・v・e(fooo!!)
Our password is an extraordinary L-O-V-E! (Fooo!!)
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(fooo!!)
My repayment is a kiss with all my love! (Fooo!!)
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting, you know?
♡作って恋にしちゃってください！
Please make a heart shape and fall in love with me!
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでいて愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this special night filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(fooo!!)
My repayment is a kiss with all my love! (Fooo!!)
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting, you know?
♡作って恋にしちゃってください！
Please make a heart shape and fall in love with me!
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでいて愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this special night filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッスで”
My return gift will be "With a kiss thrown full of love"
100万人記念 3Dライブ
[1 Million Subscriber Anniversary 3D Live]